Islam Mohamed Drissi

Senior Developer

lot el khir N 187, 16081, Baba Hassen, Algiers DZ

O zirconias in zirconias



Full-stack software developer with 4+ years industry experience specializing in cloud-driven web applications and middleware. A native of Algiers DZ, Islam enjoys hiking, cinema and video games

SKILLS Soa / Middleware JavaScript Database Environment / Proje Java intermediate Infrastructure and Ops beginr intermediate spring / spring boot esb talend mulesoft node.js angular.js jquery mysql oracle nosql agile jax-rs jax-ws jersy jms microservices rest/soap bootstrap react.js elasticsearch jenkins docker spring cloud unifie jpa / hibernate android messaging

WORK EXPERIENCE (2)

Java ee developer at ICOSNET

June 2014 - Current

https://icosnet.com/

In charge of developping web and mobile applications. using mainly JAVA programming language and other technologies when it fits our needs (php and cms/ javascript).

- Active tracking is multi-platform application (web / mobile/ crm/ erp) that uses RIFIDI-EDGE middleware to make warehouses IOT ready(java ee, android, mysql, jax-ws web services).
- Vazii is a multi-platform application that has VOIP / MESSAGING / E-FAX (java ee, android, mysql, jax-ws web services)
- Developed tooling and stand-alone applications to connect to other infrastructure products(crm, charing/billing, ticketting).
- Developed and maintained company e-commerce website (wordpress and woocommerce).

CRM Consultant/Developer at ASSA ASSOCIATES

August 2012 - June 2014

https://assa-associates.com

Developer on numerous projects being oracle peoplesoft crm technical consultant(UI, Webservices, jobs, scripts) and software developer.

- Maintained and developed UI and web services for peoplesoft crm(oracle ,toad, peoplecode, soapui).
- Developed and maintained TALEND ESB jobs to connect poeplesoft to Salesfoce crm (java, esb talend, oracle 11g).
- Developed hybrid mobile application for med-it attendies (using sencha mobile).

VOLUNTEER

Mentor at It challenge

April 2016 - April 2016

Smart and passionate people disposed with best tools and approaches taking giant leaps toward creating a business.

https://www.facebook.com/events/526574217525405/

- refining ideas
- coach and assist students.

Mentor at Start-hack

April 2016 - April 2016

A CLEVER SOLUTION TO A TRICKY PROBLEM.

http://start-hack.com

• we provide the necessary tools & materials in order to teach participants useful skills, introduce them to new technologies and push them to innovate in order to make the best hardware project.

Mentor at Hard Innovation

December 2015 - December 2015

Giving access to the rich development resources, with the goal of producing a prototype application.

https://www.facebook.com/hardinnovation/

- refining ideas.
- coach and assist students

EDUCATION (2)

JavaEE developer at Faculty of Science and Technology Settat, Morocco

java ee oracle database project management

Grade: Java ee developer

software developer at Institute of technology, bouznika, Morocco

algorithm java .net	rdbms			
Grade: Associate degree, software developer				
LANGUAGES -				
English	French	Arabic		
Intermediate	Native speaker	Native speaker		
INTERESTS —				
Wildlife	sport	Technology		

geeking reading

football basketball tennis

star wars ferrets